# Hassan, Salihu Jiyah

Albarka Estate Dakwa Tafa Abuja, +2348133101030

https://www.devcisse.com
GitHub: DevCisse (github.com)

devcisse@outlook.com

Date of birth: 07 March 1996

Languages: , English (fluent), Nupe(fluent) Yoruba (fluent), Hausa (fluent), Arabic (Intermediate)

Place of Origin: Patigi LGA, Kwara state.

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE:**

To obtain a position in an organization where I can best utilize my strong creative and critical-thinking skills - so as to attain the organizational objectives and managerial targets and goals.

#### **SUMMARY:**

A highly resourceful, flexible and innovative programmer with 3 years' experience and with an excellent team player ability to work proactively in a complex and busy office environment to enhance organizational growth, profitability and also build a solid career.

#### **SKILLS:**

- Excellent computational and analytical skills: proficient in the use of Microsoft Windows, Microsoft office packages (MS Word ,MS Access, MS Excel, MS Power Point), PHPmyadmin and a variety of generic software.
- Proficient and experienced software and website developer in a variety of languages such as C#.NET, ASP.NET, ASP.NET WEB-API, ASP.NET Core, Blazor Web Assembly, Blazor Server, Entity Framework core Entity Framework, LINQ (Language Integrated Query), JavaScript, Git, Github, Bootstrap, SQL (T-SQL, MySQL, MSS).
- Ability to work under pressure with little or no supervision, meeting demand deadlines and managing conflicting demands.
- Excellence in areas including work volume, accuracy and quality; ability to learn and master new concepts; multi task; positive work ethic; and commitment to providing unsurpassed service.
- XML, CSV reporting.
- Unit Testing with XUnit and Repository Pattern in ASP.NET CORE
- Building and consuming REST APIS
- OOP

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

### Software Developer

# • SoftTech ISSL Limited, Abuja

Mar 2020 – till date

- Programmer and Solutions Architect
  - Key responsibilities
    - Deployment of Anti-Money Laundering (AML) Software for Taj Bank Limited and Aso Savings Plc.
    - Technical Application Support at Taj Bank Limited, Aso Savings Plc, Jaiz Bank Plc.
    - Develop apps that integrate with cloud services (Salesforce)
    - Porting AML Software to Dotnet 5

## Software Developer

# • SoftTech ISSL Limited, Abuja

**April 2018 – March 2019** 

- Programmer (NYSC)
  - Key responsibilities
    - Co-design of web-based portal for IIA School of Preliminary Studies Madalla, Niger State (<a href="http://iiaspsmadalla.sch.ng/">http://iiaspsmadalla.sch.ng/</a>) (C#, Webforms, SQL Server)
    - MIS Consultant for Datech Company in the design of Web based portal for YESSO Nigeria (YESSO MIS Portal) (C#, Webforms, SQL Server)
    - Designed a web portal for Quantity Survey Registration board of Nigeria

### • Logic Gate Computers, Minna

**April 2016 – Oct 2016** 

- Software Developer (Industrial Training)
  - Key responsibilities
    - Learnt HTML, CSS, JavaScript ,JQuery and MySql
    - Developed Web Apps using PHP.
    - Basic Computer Hardware Repairs.

# **EDUCATION:**

✓ Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria

B Sc. Computer Science (Second-Class Upper division) 2017

✓ Community Secondary School Lade

Senior Secondary School Certificate 2013

✓ Tenderfoot Nursery and Primary School Ilorin

First School Leaving Certificate 2006

### **CERTIFICATIONS:**

• National Youth Service Corps (NYSC)

♦ Certificate of National Service

Microsoft Technology Associate: Database Administration Fundamentals
 (MTA)

2019